<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Waitress Turned Computer Geek]]></title>
  <link href="http://kellihsf.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kellihsf.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-08T17:46:51-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://kellihsf.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kelli Hackethal]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to school: Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://kellihsf.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/back-to-school-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T20:35:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://kellihsf.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/back-to-school-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the title suggests, it is yet indeed the first day of school for me. I am taking the DaVinci
Coder&rsquo;s course titled &ldquo;Building the Toolbelt of a Junior Ruby on Rails Developer.&rdquo; This class
is a full immersion RoR based training that lasts for a short 11 weeks.</p>

<p>Our first assignment was to get a blog up and running. The purpose of this blog is for
students to talk about their experiences throughout the class, what&rsquo;s being taught,
technical issues and any other information that will be helpful to refer to or perhaps help
someone else who is learning the same material.</p>

<p>Helpful programs to check out:</p>

<p>Evernote: Great for taking notes in class <br>
Anki: Flashcard application for quizzing yourself on definitions, topics, concepts, etc.. <br>
Github: A code sharing and publishing website <br>
Airparrot: Allows students to mirror their screen on to the class projector; helpful for solving problems that other students might be having too <br>
Moom: Lets you move and zoom windows easily all through the keyboard shortcuts</p>

<p>My goals for this blog is to: <br>
Keep it updated and blog about something after each class; <br>
Help others who might be learning from a beginning level; <br>
Be a great reference tool to track my progress and refer back to any questions
or problems I had. <br></p>

<br>


<p>Books that are helpful for a beginner learning RoR:</p>

<p>Learn to Program by: Chris Pine <br>
Beginning Ruby from Novice to Professional by: Peter Cooper</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
